<chapter id="monitoring_introduction">
	<title>Introduction</title>

	<para>
		InfraRED is an open source performance tool to monitor JavaEE based application performance. 
		By using Aspect, it collects data to measure performance and reports data analysis result.
		Anyframe Monitoring Tool fixes diverse infraRED(
		<ulink url="http://infrared.sourceforge.net/versions/latest/">http://infrared.sourceforge.net</ulink>)
		 based bugs inherited within infraRED and provides enhanced UI. 
		Next, basic structure of InfraRED, foundation of Anyframe Monitoring Tool and major features of Anyframe Monitoring Tool will be discussed.
	</para>

	<section id="monitoring_introduction_sec001">
		<title>Basic structure</title>

		<para>Infrared basically consists of Agent, Collector, and GUI as shown in picture below.</para>

		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata align="center"
					fileref="../image/monitoring/architecture.png" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Agent : to collect and integrate data on application implementation based on request 
					from application to be monitored and send them to Collector
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					Collector : to combine data delivered from different agents and store them in DB.
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					GUI : to exhibit collected data in diverse forms to users by asking query to Collector. 
					Anyframe Monitoring Tool uses Ajax based Google Web Tool Kit or GWT as basis and offers more convenient, 
					efficient and enhanced UI.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>

	<section id="monitoring_introduction_sec002">
		<title>Major features</title>

		<para>As below are major features provided at Anyframe Monitoring Tool.</para>

		<table>
			<title>Major features - #1</title>
			<tgroup cols="2">
				<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="2*"/>
				<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="3*"/>		
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry align="center">Major features</entry>
						<entry align="center">description</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>

				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>Statistics</entry>
						<entry>
							Absolute module, Hierarchical modle and monitoring statistics on final call are shown.
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							Performance statistics for various elements, jsp, http,
							etc.
						</entry>
						<entry>Each layer of SQL, JDBC, JSP, HTTP displays monitoring statistics.</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>Graphs</entry>
						<entry>Data analysis is supported with three-dimensional graph, color labels and Tooltip labels.</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>

		<table>
			<title>Major features - #2</title>
			<tgroup cols="2">
				<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="2*"/>
				<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="3*"/>		
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry align="center">Major features</entry>
						<entry align="center">Description</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>

				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>Charts</entry>
						<entry>
							A total run time, running numbers and percentage point over a total implementation 
							on called commands are offered in the form of easy representation.
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>Better readable SQL's</entry>
						<entry>For easy representation of query statement, 
						all queries are changed in capitals and their words are spaced.</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>Hierarchical Views</entry>
						<entry>
							For easy representation of data analysis result, 
							data, percentage point and percentage point bar graph use coloring.
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>Multiple Applications</entry>
						<entry>The configuration allows checking of monitoring result on various applications.</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>Reporting</entry>
						<entry>It supports the report creation in the format of Excel, PDF, HTML, CSV.</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>Refresh or Reset</entry>
						<entry>
							It supports Refresh feature to reset collected data up to now or update the latest implementation contents.
						</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
	</section>
</chapter>
