<chapter id="monitoring_views">
	<title>Views</title>

	<para>
		Anyframe Monitoring Tool is divided into two: 
		Select Application Window for the application selection to be monitored and Panel showing monitoring results in a various form.
	</para>

	<section id="monitoring_views_sa">
		<title>Select Application</title>

		<para>
			Anyframe Monitoring Tool allows users to choose a monitoring object and method at Select Application window.
			Next, areas consisting of Select Application window will be discussed.
		</para>

		<section id="monitoring_views_sa_sec001">
			<title>formation</title>

			<para>
				Select Application window is divided into three: Select Application, 
				Select monitoring period and Reset period. 
				Offered is the selection functionality for “Show labels for graphs” additionally.
			</para>

			<section id="monitoring_views_sa_sec001_sec001">
				<title>Select Application</title>

				<para>
					The list of application monitored associating with Anyframe Monitoring Tool is shown in tree format.
					Users can select subject application from a tree list. 
				</para>

				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center"
							fileref="../image/monitoring/amt1.jpg" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>

			<section id="monitoring_views_sa_sec001_sec002">
				<title>Select monitoring period</title>

				<para>
					An area for defining monitoring data collection method can be selected either at “Live Data” and “Archive Mode”. 
					Live Data means real-time monitoring. 
					And Archive mode means monitoring on collected data on a set frequency after setting time interval. 
				</para>

				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center"
							fileref="../image/monitoring/amt2.jpg" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>

			<section id="monitoring_views_sa_sec001_sec003">
				<title>Reset period</title>

				<para>This area is to define the frequency at a minute interval for resetting collected data for monitoring.</para>
			</section>

			<section id="monitoring_views_sa_sec001_sec004">
				<title>Show labels for graph</title>

				<para>
					When monitoring result is shown in graph, the feature allows users to select to show labels, as well. 
					Graph is shown with different sizes and colors according to running time and frequency. 
					When Show label for graph is selected, graph is shown with label as below.
				</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center"
							fileref="../image/monitoring/amt4.jpg" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="monitoring_views_panels">
		<title>Panels</title>

		<para>
			Anyframe Monitoring Tools are divided into three: 
			Top area, Left area and Right area. F
			unctionalities such as Report, Refresh and Reset are provided at Top area; 
			three panels are shown at Left area; monitoring results for each panel is displayed at Right area. 
			Next, details on Top and Left areas will be discussed.
		</para>

		<section id="monitoring_views_panels_sec001">
			<title>Absolute Panel</title>

			<para>
				Anyframe  Monitoring Tool allows the classification of monitoring subject layer 
				such as HTTP, APPLICATION_SERVICE, JDBC, SQL and a total run-time and call frequency. 
			</para>

			<section id="monitoring_views_panels_sec001_sec001">
				<title>Summary Tab - general</title>

				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center"
							fileref="../image/monitoring/amt5.jpg" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>

				<para>
					Summary tab exhibits a total run time, call frequency, 
					average time, minimum runtime, maximum runtime, first execution time, last execution time and adjusted average. 
				</para>

				<table>
					<title>Summary Tab item</title>
					<tgroup cols="2">
						<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="3*"/>
						<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="7*"/>					
						<thead>
							<row>
								<entry align="center">item</entry>
								<entry align="center">description</entry>
							</row>
						</thead>					
						<tbody>
							<row>
								<entry>a total run time</entry>
								<entry>the time elapsed per one call</entry>
							</row>

							<row>
								<entry>call numbers</entry>
								<entry>a total runtime numbers</entry>
							</row>

							<row>
								<entry>average time</entry>
								<entry>average runtime to handle a call</entry>
							</row>

							<row>
								<entry>minimum and maximum runtime</entry>
								<entry>minimum and maximum runtime out of run-time</entry>
							</row>

							<row>
								<entry>initial or final runtime</entry>
								<entry>initial or final runtime out of a series of calls</entry>
							</row>

							<row>
								<entry>adjusted average</entry>
								<entry>average runtime except initial runtime</entry>
							</row>
						</tbody>
					</tgroup>
				</table>

				<para>
					* In need of deeper understanding of numbers shown on Anyframe Monitoring Tools, 
					please refer to <link linkend="monitoring_views_panels_sec007"> 
					[reference] Interpreting Layer Number </link> below this page.
				</para>
			</section>

			<section id="monitoring_views_panels_sec001_sec002">
				<title>Trace Tab</title>

				<para>
					Running information per each layer is traceable and trace path is shown with a total runtime and a total call number at trace tab. 
					Next, blue bar shown at trace tab will be discussed. 
				</para>

				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center"
							fileref="../image/monitoring/amt6.jpg" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>

				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Bar at root operation is fully colored with the longest length.</para>
					</listitem>

					<listitem>
						<para>
							The total length of operation bar called by upper-level operation is the same as that of colored section at upper-level bar.
						</para>
					</listitem>

					<listitem>
						<para>
							Colored section per each operation shows a percentage point of a total runtime of relevant section by that of upper-level section.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>

				<para>These bars allow monitoring of application bottleneck state.</para>
			</section>

			<section id="monitoring_views_panels_sec001_sec003">
				<title>Summary Tab - SQL</title>

				<para>
					The next picture shows the top five query statements based on query call intervals through summary tab. 
					The total query statement implemented can be checked at tooltip.
				</para>

				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center"
							fileref="../image/monitoring/amt9.jpg" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>

				<para>
					The table in the above picture is divided in Prepared and Execute statement, showing data. 
					Prepared and Eexcute statement means JDBC method called to handle a certain request.
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>

		<section id="monitoring_views_panels_sec002">
			<title>Hierarchical Panel</title>

			<para>
				Hiearatchical panel describes a layer name as call relationship between layers classified with “.” 
				Mark and suggests data document on layer expressed at the last part. 
				(For example, HTTP.APPLICATION_LAYER.JDBC displays information on JDBC layer called from HTTP.APPLICATION_LAYYER.)
			</para>

			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../image/monitoring/amt10.jpg" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>

			<para>Monitoring results in the same type with Absolute Panel can be checked at Hierarchical Panel,too.</para>
		</section>

		<section id="monitoring_views_panels_sec003">
			<title>Last Invocation Panel</title>

			<para>
				Last Invocation panel provides a track down method regarding a few lastly called running flows. 
				The chart shows a total running time and numbers.
			</para>

			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../image/monitoring/amt14.jpg" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>

			<para>
				It is likely that sequence invocation is counted either just once or a few times per sequence shown at Last Invocation Panel. 
				In the case of operation calling other operation included in stack trace, more than one count is in the high likelihood.  
				Otherwise, if operation does not call other operations, stack trace is not included and will be counted only once.
			</para>
		</section>

		<section id="monitoring_views_panels_sec004">
			<title>Report</title>

			<para>
				This feature is to report monitoring results in a various document format. 
				The click of Report link will lead to opening of Report Wizard. 
				A slew of reports will be created based on selected value per each Step.
			</para>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Step1 : The selection of report format.</para>

					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center"
								fileref="../image/monitoring/amt17.jpg" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>Step 2 : The selection of panel for reporting subject. 
					( The selection between Absolute module and Hierarchical module)</para>

					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center"
								fileref="../image/monitoring/amt18.jpg" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>Step 3 : The selection of detailed information on report contents. </para>

					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center"
								fileref="../image/monitoring/amt19.jpg" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>
						Step 4 : The selection of report contents. 
						Determine whether to select a few top data out of the whole data, display in value or in diagram, or both.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center"
								fileref="../image/monitoring/amt20.jpg" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>
						Step 5 : If Finish button is clicked, summary of selected information on report to be created is on display. 
						And if Download button is clicked, created report can be downloaded locally.
					</para>

					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center"
								fileref="../image/monitoring/amt21.jpg" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>

			<para>The next picture is the report example when the report format is in the form of Excel. </para>

			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../image/monitoring/amt22.jpg" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>

		<section id="monitoring_views_panels_sec005">
			<title>Refresh</title>

			<para>
				The feature is to check monitoring results on running information changeable on a real-time basis. 
				If Refresh button is clicked, the currant status of application is scanned once again, renewing real-time monitoring information.
			</para>
		</section>

		<section id="monitoring_views_panels_sec006">
			<title>Reset</title>

			<para>
				Reset feature is to erase data collected up to now and initialize. 
				Be aware that if Reset link is clicked, all the collected data will be deleted.
			</para>
		</section>

		<section id="monitoring_views_panels_sec007">
			<title>[Reference] Interpreting Layer Number</title>

			<para>
				From now on, values shown on Anyframe Monitoring Tool will be discussed. A deeper understanding is in order for efficient use of the tool.
			</para>

			<para>
				Under the normal conditions, a total running time of lower-levels is equal to that of upper-level. 
				However, the next picture shows otherwise.
			</para>

			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/monitoring/exclusivemode.jpg" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>

			<para>
				The above pictures show that the total running time value at the lower level is 3125(ms), 
				however, the total running time of APPLICATION_SERVICE including lower level is 2484(ms).
			</para>
			
			<para>In this case, the understanding of multi-threading should precede.</para>

			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../image/monitoring/C.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>

			<para>
				As shown in the above picture, let’s assume a method to connect layer x starting point and final point. 
				Three methods are simultaneously implemented at two separate threads. 
				Method A is implemented at 70ms, with Method B 50ms and Method C 30ms. However, the total running time for Layer X is 80ms. 
				(70+50+30 is not equal to 150ms) because these methods are being implemented at two threads at the same time.
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
